A Finding Aid to the James D. Smillie and Smillie family papers, 1853-1957, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
James D. Smillie and Smillie family papers
1853-1957
Archives of American Art
Smillie Family
AAA.smilsmil
Archival Resource Key
5.6 Linear feet
The James D. Smillie and Smillie family papers measure 5.6 linear feet and date from 1853 to 1957. The collection consists of the papers of four members of the Smillie family including James Smillie, his sons James David and George Henry Smillie, and George's wife, Helen 'Nellie' Jacobs Smillie. The majority of the papers are those of James D. Smillie, comprised of correspondence, forty-five daily diaries, a scrapbook, printed materials, and one etching. The papers of James Smillie consist of biographical materials and writings. The George Smillie papers include biographical materials, scattered correspondence, a scrapbook, printed materials, and photographs. The Helen Jacobs Smillie papers include corrrespondence and photographs. Also found are scattered materials relating to other family members, mostly the children of Helen Jacobs and George Smillie.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
James Smillie, David Smillie, and Barbara Smillie Curtis donated the Smillie Family papers to the Archives of American Art in several installments between 1978 and 1990. James Smille lent photographs for microfilming in 1986.
Related Material
Also found in the Archives of American Art is the Brucia Witthoft research material on James Smillie and the Smillie family, 1830- 1999. The National Gallery of Canada holds the James D. Smillie Papers.
Alternative Forms Available
The collection was digitized in its entirety in 2012 and is available via the Archives of American Art's website.
Materials lent for microfilming are available on 35mm microfilm reels 3766 and 3829 at the Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Biographical Note
James D. Smillie and the Smillie family members were active in New York City and the New England area as engravers and landscape painters during the nineteenth century. Members of the Smillie Family of artists include James Smillie (1807-1885), his sons James D. (1833-1909) and George Smillie (1854-1924), and George's wife Helen 'Nellie' Jacobs Smillie (1855-1926).
Born in Edinburgh, Scotland to David and Elizabeth Smillie, James Smillie immigrated to Quebec, Canada. James must have learned engraving from his father who worked with jewelry and silver. Upon his father's death in 1827, Smillie travelled to London and eventually to New York City, where he embarked on a career of creating engravings of paintings by other artists. By 1831, he had established his reputation primarily as an engraver of American landscape paintings. The portability of James Smillie's engravings helped to bring to the American public the grand landscapes by Albert Bierstadt, Thomas Cole, and Asher Durand. Smillie also worked for the American Banknote Company.
James Smillie married Catherine Van Valkenburg in 1832, and two of their sons, James David and George Henry also became artists. Elder son James D. assisted his father with engraving and later explored his own artistic talents in prints of the American landscape. Among his many subjects were the Sierra Nevada, Adirondack, Rocky, White, and Catskill Mountains. James D. Smillie was a founding member of the American Watercolor Society and served as its president from 1873 to 1879. Additionally, he was an early member of the New York Etching Club and the first meeting was held in his studio in 1877. James D. also wrote about art for various periodicals.
Like his older brother, George Henry Smillie learned engraving from his father, but turned to painting early in his career. By 1862, he had his own studio in New York City and exhibited with the National Academy of Design in 1864. George travelled throughout the United States sketching and painting landscapes inspired by Long Island, the Adirondack Mountains, the Rocky Mountains, and New England. Many of George's paintings of the American West were influenced by the Hudson River School. George married one of his brother's pupils, Helen Sheldon Jacobs.
Helen Jacobs Smillie, known as Nellie, was born in New York City to Samuel and Helen Jacobs. She received art instruction at Cooper Union and the National Academy of Design and was a pupil of James D. Smillie and J. O. Eaton. She married George Smillie in 1881, with whom she had three sons, Sheldon, Charles, and Gordon. Nellie was a member of the American Watercolor Society along with her husband and brother-in-law, and painted in the Hudson River School style.
Scope and Content Note
The James D. Smillie and Smillie family papers measure 5.6 linear feet and date from 1853 to 1957. The collection consists of the papers of four members of the Smillie family including James Smillie, his sons James David and George Henry Smillie, and George's wife, Helen 'Nellie' Jacobs Smillie. The majority of the papers are those of James D. Smillie, comprised of correspondence, forty-five daily diaries, a scrapbook, printed materials, and one etching. The papers of James Smillie consist of biographical materials and writings. The George Smillie papers include biographical materials, scattered correspondence, a scrapbook, printed materials, and photographs. The Helen Jacobs Smillie papers include correspondence and photographs. Also found are scattered materials relating to other family members, mostly the children of Helen Jacobs and George Smillie.
James David Smillie's papers consist of correspondence, personal business records, forty-five diaries, a scrapbook, and printed material. Correspondence is mostly professional in nature and includes letters from Albert Bierstadt, Frederick Stuart Church, Samuel Colman, Charles Henry Hart, Eastman Johnson, James Smillie, and A. T. Tait. Forty-five volumes of detailed daily diaries dating from 1865 until 1909 include entries about his work, but are exceedingly rich in references to over 200 artists with which Smillie was associated. Additionally, there are numerous loose documents, notes, and some photographs that were found tucked within the diaries. This finding aid includes a list of named artists referenced in the diaries along with the exact date of the notation. James D. Smillie's papers also include an original etching entitled Up the Hill.
James Smillie papers are scattered and include manuscript and draft copies of his published autobiography, A Pilgrimage, and memorabilia from his 50th wedding anniversary to Catherine Van Valkenburg Smillie.
George Henry Smillie papers contain biographical materials, scattered correspondence, a scrapbook of clippings, printed materials, and photographs. There is a certificate from the National Academy of Design dating from 1883 and photographs of Smillie, Smillie in his studio, and his family.
Helen Jacobs Smillie papers consist of family correspondence from her husband and parents, and studio portrait photographs.
Scattered papers from other family members include correspondence, a list of works of art by the family, a photograph album from Sheldon Smillie, and a portrait of William Smillie.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 5 series:
Missing Title
Series 1: James D. Smillie papers, 1853-1917 (4.5 linear feet; Boxes 1-7)
Series 2: James Smillie papers, 1882 (0.2 linear feet; Box 5)
Series 3: George Henry Smillie papers, 1867-1920 (0.6 linear feet; Boxes 5-6)
Series 4: Helen Jacobs Smillie papers, 1860-1910 (0.1 linear feet; Box 5)
Series 5: Other Smillie Family Members papers, circa 1880s-1957 (0.2 linear feet; Box 5)
Separated Materials
The Archives of American Art also holds materials lent for microfilming (reels 3766 and 3829) including personal photographs, photos of Smille's house in Montrose, Pennsylvania, and a photocopy of a journal. Lent material was returned to the lenders and is not described in the collection container inventory.
Other Finding Aids
An index to artists mentioned in the James D. Smillie diaries (microfilm reels 2849-2854) is available at the Archives of American Art's Washington, D.C. office.
Diaries; Etchings; Artists' studios -- Photographs; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Art, Modern -- 19th century -- New York (State) -- New York; Artists -- New York (State) -- New York; Painters -- New York (State) -- New York; Engraving -- 19th century -- United States; Engravers -- New York (State) -- New York; Hart, Charles Henry, 1847-1918; Smillie, Catherine Van Valkenburg; Colman, Samuel, 1832-1920; Johnson, Eastman, 1824-1906; Church, Frederick S. (Frederick Stuart), 1842-1924; Bierstadt, Albert, 1830-1902; Tait, A.T.; Smillie, Nellie Sheldon Jacobs, 1854-1926; Smillie, James, 1807-1885; Smillie, James David, 1833-1909; Smillie, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1921
- James David Smillie papers, 1853-1917; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 4.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-7
  Scope and Contents note
  The James David Smillie papers consist of correspondence, personal business records, 45 daily diaries spanning 1865-1909, a scrapbook of clippings, printed materials, and artwork.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged as 6 subseries.
  Missing Title
  1.1: Correspondence, 1850-1905
  1.2: Personal Business Records, 1863-1909
  1.3: Diaries, 1865-1909
  1.4: Scrapbook, circa 1850s-1900
  1.5: Printed Material, 1865-1917
  1.6: Artwork, circa 1879
  Existence and Location of Copies
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - Correspondence, 1850-1905; 1.1; Archival Resource Key
    The bulk of this subseries is comprised of correspondence with artists and colleagues including Albert Bierstadt, Frederick Stuart Church, Samuel Coleman, Charles Henry Hart, and Eastman Johnson. There are three pieces of personal correspondence to his wife, Anna, and from his father and uncle, Charles Smillie.
    Arrangement note
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent with miscellaneous drafts of outgoing letters filed at the bottom.
    - Bierstadt, Albert, circa 1863-1869; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bierstadt, Edward, 1863; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Church, Frederick Stuart, 1878 or 1879; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Colman, Samuel, 1871-1906; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Curtis, George M., 1886; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ehninger, John Whetton, 1882; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Includes printed material from Tom Cobb for the Saratoga Humane Society.
    - Haden, Francis Seymour, circa 1890s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Hart, Charles Henry, 1884; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Hitchcock, Ripley, circa 1890; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Hogarth and Sons, 1882; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Huntington, Daniel B., 1850-1885; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Jenkins, Will, 1902; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Johnson, Eastman, 1886; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Lossing, Bevden (?), 1883; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Mathers, Frank Jewell, 1905; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Art Editor of the Evening Post, includes clippings.
    - Smillie, Anna Cook, 1853; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Smillie, Charles F., 1893; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Smillie, James, 1875; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Tait, A. T., 1898; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Waters, M. G., 1901; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous Outgoing Letters, circa 1902; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Personal Business Records, 1863-1909; 1.2; Archival Resource Key
    Scattered business records include an agreement between Albert Bierstadt and James D. Smillie concerning the engraving of Forest Glen, donations, loans, and sales records, and a list of works in the Smillie collection.
    - Agreement, 1863 May 6; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Donation Records, 1908-1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Loans and Sales Records, 1882; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Smillie Collection Lists, 1901; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Diaries, 1865-1909; 1.3; Archival Resource Key
    There are forty-five volumes of daily diaries in which Smillie describes his paintings, drawings and prints, and references over 200 artists with whom he was acquainted. Loose items originally filed within the diaries include letters, notes, sketches, a silhouette, calling cards, receipts, printed material, and a photo of Smillie, among many other items.
    See Appendix for a list of artists mentioned in the diaries from Series 1.3.
    This subseries is arranged in chronological order with materials tucked into diaries at the end of the subseries and arranged by type. The loose items had been removed from the diaries at an earlier time, most likely upon microfilming, and it is not clear in which diary they were originally filed.
    Appendix: Artists Mentioned in James David Smillie's Diaries, 1865-1880
    Abbey, Edwin A.: 1877 May 11, Dec 18; 1878 Jan 10, Jan 11, Jan 22, Jan 25, Jan 28, Mar 9, Mar 11, Apr 30
    Anderson, A.: 1873 Feb 8
    Augero, Francesco: 1867 Apr 23; 1868 Feb 10, Feb 1, Jun 5, Oct 30, Nov 17, Nov 19, Dec 4, Dec 17; 1869 Jul 10; 1870 Mar 22, Apr 9, Jun 9; 1871 Oct 3; 1872 Nov 5; 1873 Jan 8, Feb 8, Apr 18, May 13, May 23, Jun 20, Dec 19; 1875 Jun 18, Dec 6; 1876 Jan 2
    Baldwin, A. H.: 1875 Mar 5; 1877 Feb 27, Mar 1, Mar 5, Mar 6, May 2; 1878 Jan 24; 1880 Apr 12
    Bascom, Marie Louise (Mrs. James R. Brevoort): 1868 Dec 19; 1871 May 9, May 26; 1872 Feb 28, May 1, Nov 4, Nov 11, Nov 15, Nov 20
    Beard, William H.: 1871 Nov 2, Nov 23; 1872 Jan 27, May 9; 1873 Feb 1; 1877 Jan 21; 1880 Mar 18
    Beers, Julie: 1868 Jun 16, Nov 7, Nov 11; 1870 Mar 12, Mar 31; 1871 Dec 9; 1872 Oct 30; 1873 Mar 10; 1875 Dec 28; 1876 Feb 25
    Bellows, Albert Fitch: 1867 Feb 6; 1868 Jan 18, Apr 16; 1871 Jan 10, Jan 16, Mar 15, Nov 23; 1872 Jan 26, Feb 1, May 7; 1873 Feb 4, Feb 13, Mar 5, May 27, Nov 27; 1874 Jan 27, Feb 5, Feb 11, Feb 25; 1875 Jan 28, Feb 3, Feb 4, Feb 6, Feb 8, Feb 17, Nov 5, Nov, 12; 1876 Jan 14, Jan 17, Mar 20, May 16, Nov 9, Nov 20, Dec 14, Dec 18, Dec 19, Dec 22; 1877 Feb 15, Mar 16, Apr 30, May 9, Oct 23, Nov 9, Nov 21, Dec 14; 1878 Feb 4, May 19, Dec 22; 1879 Jan 12, Feb 20, Mar 16, May 13, Nov 14; 1880 Jan 3, May 10, Nov 3, Nov 16
    Bierstadt, Albert: 1866 May 10
    Blackman, Walter: 1868 Aug 22, Aug 24, Sep 13; 1870 Oct 22; 1871 Oct 3, Oct 31
    Blauvelt, Miss H. J.: 1872 Jan 22; 1876 Jan 25, May 19; 1877 Feb 22
    Blodgett, William: 1871 Jan 20, Jan 26
    Bradford, William: 1872 Feb 22
    Brevoort, James Renwick: 1865 Apr 24; 1866 Jan 5, Jan 6, Mar 19; 1867 Jan 4, Apr 23, Oct 25, Nov 20; 1868 Feb 14, Feb 19, Feb 26, Mar 18, Apr 18, May 4, Jun 1; 1869 Oct 11, Oct 30; 1870 Oct 20, Nov 1, Dec 10, Dec 17, Dec 23, Dec 24, Dec 31; 1871 Jan 7, Feb 4, Feb 11, Feb 18, Feb 22, Feb 25, Mar 22, Apr 15, Oct 3; 1872 Feb 1, Apr 24; 1873 Feb 5, Apr 8, Apr 9; 1878 Dec 18
    Bricher, Alfred Thompson: 1873 Dec 27; 1875 Nov 12, Dec 2, Dec 10; 1875 Mar 20, Nov 3, Nov 30, Dec 14; 1876 Mar 1, Dec 14
    Brown, John George: 1867 Feb 19; 1870 Apr 29, Dec 2; 1872 Mar 25, Nov 20; 1873 Nov 8; 1874 Jan 8, Apr 4, May 5, Jun 24, Dec 7; 1875 May 22, Nov 2, Nov 3, Nov 30, Dec 14; 1876 Feb 25, Mar 1, Nov 20, Dec 18; 1877 Feb 5, Feb 15, Feb 20, Mar 16, Mar 20, Mar 27; 1878 Mar 6, Dec 7, Dec 20; 1880 Jan 31, Mar 26, Jun 5; 1880 Dec 23
    Brown, Walter: 1869, Jan 27, Dec 8; 1870 Mar 10, Mar 12; 1872 Dec 10, Dec 12; 1873 Jan 21, Feb 5; 1874 Jan 3, Jan 18, Jan 20, Feb 5, Apr 3, May 12, May 14, May 15, Jun 11, Dec 5, Dec 10; 1875 Mar 24; 1878 Mar 19
    Burling, Frederick Gilbert: 1867 Feb 6, Mar 6, Jun 4, Oct 24, Nov 11, Nov 25, Dec 19; 1868 Jan 31, Apr 16, May 7, Sep 14, Oct 31, Nov 2, Nov 12; 1869 Jan 11, Jan 16, Nov 12, Dec 16, Dec 16; 1870 Jan 4, Jan 10, Feb 16, May 3, Jun 6, Jun 24, Nov 1, Nov 18; 1871 Jan 31, Feb 4, Oct 3; 1873 Feb 1, Apr 22; 1874 Jan 6, Jan 17, Feb 4, Feb 9, May 20, Jun 3; 1875 Feb 8
    Butler, H.: 1872 Apr 4
    Calvery, Charles: 1870 Dec 13; 1873 Feb 25, May 26; 1874 Jun 9; 1876 Jan 28, May 12, Dec 30; 1878 May 6, Oct 10; 1879 Mar 12, Apr 7
    Carpenter, Francis Bicknell: 1872 Apr 10; 1873 (no date)
    Casilear, John W.: 1872 Jan 27, 1875 May 22
    Champney, Benjamin: 1867 Aug 1, Sep 24
    Campney, [no first name]: 1879 Jan 16; 1880 Feb 4
    Chase, William Merritt: 1880 Sep 11
    Church, Frederick Edwin: 1877 Apr 22
    Church, Frederick S.: 1879 Dec 1; 1880 Apr 14
    Church, [no first name]: 1869 Dec 31; 1878 Jan 24, Jan 29
    Colman, Samuel Jr.: 1867 Jan 5, Mar 6, Jun 4, Jun 27, Nov 5, Nov 25, Dec 2, Dec 18, Dec 26; 1868 Feb 2, Feb 25, Apr 16, Jun 3, Jun 9, Jul 22, Aug 8, Aug 12, Aug 13, Aug 15, Aug 26, Aug 29, Aug 30, Aug 31, Sep 1, Sep 6, Sep 7, Sep 8, Sep 10, Sep 16, Sep 23, Sep 25, Nov 2, Nov 10, Nov 12, Nov 21, Dec 10, Dec 15; 1869 Jan 17, Jan 18, Jan 21, Feb 23, Mar 8, Mar 9, May 4, May 8, Jun 2, Jul 9, Jul 16, Jul 17, Aug 16, Aug 18, Aug 19, Aug 21, Aug 23, Aug 24, Aug 25, Aug 28, Aug 30, Sep 4, Sep 12, Sep 13, Sep 15, Sep 16, Sep 17, Sep 19, Sep 22, Sep 28, Sep 30, Oct 28, Nov 13, Nov 16; 1870 Jan 29, Apr 30, Jun 13, Jun 15, Jun 27, Jun 29, Jul 5, Aug 14, Nov 1, Dec 13; 1871 Jan 7, Jan 24, Jun 15, Jun 16, Oct 3, Nov 14, Nov 15, Dec 1; 1872 Jan 12, Jan 26, Jan 27, Jan 30, Feb 2, Feb 19, Feb 28, Mar 28, Apr 4, Apr 11, Apr 12, Apr 13, May 6, May 17, Jun 6, Nov 25, Dec 9; 1873 Jan 15, Mar 30, Jun 12; 1874 Apr 25, May 31, Dec 3; 1875 Jun 13, Aug 12, Sep 3, Sep 14, Oct 22, Oct 26, Oct 27, Nov 2, Nov 8, Nov 22, Dec 14; 1876 Jan 11, Jan 12, Jan 29, Feb 5, Feb 15, Feb 27, Mar 3, Apr 19, Apr 20, Apr 23, May 12, May 15, May 20, Jun 18, Nov 4, Nov 10, Nov 12, Nov 14, Nov 21, Dec 10, Dec 18, Dec 22; 1877 Mar 16, Mar 28, Apr 10, May 9, Jun 20, Oct 9, Oct 24, Oct 26, Nov 2, Nov 18, Nov 21, Nov 28, Nov 29, Dec 5; 1878 Jan 3, Jan 9, Feb 6, Feb 13, Feb 14, Mar 8, Mar 12, Mar 17, Mar 20, Mar 21, Mar 25, Apr 6, Apr 8, Apr 10, Apr 16, Apr 19, Apr 27, May 4, May 23, May 27, May 30, Jun 1, Jun 5, Jun 6, Aug 9, Aug 11, Aug 12, Aug 26, Aug 29, Aug 30, Oct 10, Nov 16, Nov 22; 1879 Jan 12, Mar 4, Mar 12, Mar 23, Mar 28, May 5, May 16, May 21, Jun 10, Jun 12, Oct 12, Oct 13, Nov 18, Nov 27, Dec 8, Dec 16, Dec 21; 1880 Jan 4, Jan 9, Feb 13, Feb 25, Mar 26, Apr 12, Apr 21, Apr 30, May 18, Oct 21, Oct 26, Nov 3, Nov 6, Nov 7, Nov 28, Dec 6, Dec 27
    Colyer, Vincent: 1874 Feb 25, Feb 28
    Covell, Margaret: 1874 Apr 11, Jun 24
    Craig, William B.: 1867 Dec 16; 1871 Nov 16; 1873 Feb 11
    Cranch, Christopher Pearce: 1867 Dec 12; 1868 May 7, Nov 22; 1869 Oct 29, Dec 7, Dec 10; 1870 Jan 18, Jan 19; 1872 Feb 20; 1879 Aug 5
    Cropsey, Jasper Francis: 1867 Dec 16; 1869 Nov 2; 1871 Feb 4; 1878 Mar 20
    Culver, "Of Chicago": 1871 Jan 13, Jan 19, Mar 6; 1871 May 9; 1874 Mar 5, Dec 16; 1875 Mar 20; 1876 Dec 30
    Culverhouse, Johann Mongles: 1870 Dec 27; 1875 Apr 29
    Dana, William Parsons Winchester: 1868 Jan 24; 1870 Apr 29
    Dolph, John Henry: 1876 Jan 14; 1877 Mar 14
    Darley, Felix O. C.: 1869 Jan 20, Jul 3; 1873 Feb 11, Dec 1; 1874 Jan 22, Jan 26, Mar 7, Mar 29, Apr 3; 1877 Mar 13
    De Forest, Lockwood: 1872 Apr 8
    De Haas, Mauritz or Maurice Frederick: 1867 Dec 3; 1870 Feb 1, Apr 29; 1872 Sep 11; 1874 Apr 14; 1876 Feb 25
    Delnoce, Lewis (Luigi): 1879 Jun 6; 1880 Aug 16
    Dodge, W. E.: 1868 Mar 14; 1969 Nov 27
    Dunn, Alexander Gordon: 1871 Feb 4
    Durand, Asher Benjamin: 1866 Feb 22; 1867 Nov 4; 1868 Sep 8, Sep 10, Sep 13, Sep 15; 1870 Aug 18, Aug 21, Sep 11, Sep 16, Sep 24, Sep 26; 1872 Feb 12; 1880 Nov 5
    Durfee, Rose: 1876 Dec 30; 1877 Jan 21, Mar 1, Mar 14, Apr 22, Apr 30, Jun 1, Nov 1, Nov 7; 1878 Mar 13, Apr 17, Nov 27; 1880 May 11
    Eaton, Joseph Oriel: 1867 Feb 21; 1869 Feb 27, Mar 11, Mar 15, Nov 15; 1870 Feb 26, Apr 29; 1871 Dec 30; 1873 Feb 3, Dec 4; 1874 Jan 17, Dec 16; 1875 Feb 8
    Eaton, Wyatt; 1878 Jun 1
    Ehninger, John Whetton: 1866 Jul 1, Jul 3, Jul 16, Aug 10, Aug 14; 1867 Feb 19; 1869 Jan 20; 1880 Jan 12, Apr, 16 Apr 19, Jul 14, Jul 16, Jul 17, Jul 20, Jul 21-30, Aug 2
    Elliot, Miss: 1869 Sep 2, Sep 3, Sep 24, Sep 27, Sep 30; 1870 Apr 19
    Fairman, James: 1866 May 16; 1867 Oct 24, Oct 26, Oct 28; 1868 Mar 6; 1870 Mar 20, Dec 13
    Falconer, John M.: 1870 Apr 29; 1873 Feb 1; 1874 Jan 9, Jan 12, Jan 22, Mar 7, Apr 19, Dec 10; 1875 Jan 5; 1878 Jan 25; 1879 Jun 18, Jun 19, Nov 22, Dec 16
    Farrer, Henry: 1867 Mar 6, Dec 17; 1869 Jan 20; 1871 Apr 27; 1873 Feb 3, Mar 12; 1877 Jan 8, Feb 5, Dec 10; 1880 Jun 1, Nov 3, Nov 12, Nov 16
    Fenn, Harry: 1867 Mar 6; 1869 Apr 1; 1870 Jan 28; 1872 Jul 20; 1873 Mar 10, Nov 27, Dec 26; 1874 Jan 14, Dec 3; 1875 Jul 15
    Ferguson, Henry A.: 1868 Aug 24, Sep 13; 1869 Oct 14; 1870 Mar 11, Mar 26, May 3, Jul 21, Sep 24; 1871 Jan 11, May 2, Sep 3; 1872 Jun 5, Aug 17; 1873 Mar 20, Aug 2, Oct 31, Nov 6, Nov 22, Dec 8, Dec 10, Dec 17, Dec 23; 1874 Jan 6, Jan 8, Jan 12, Jan 13, Jan 15, Feb 2, Feb 10, Feb 28, Mar 7, Mar 24, Jun 3, Jun 6, Jun 11, Oct 7, Oct 31, Nov 14, Dec 18; 1875 Apr 19, May 21, Jun 27, Sep 14; 1876 Jun 10; 1877 May 3; 1878 Jan 6, Jun 29, Oct 4, Dec 18; 1879 Dec 12
    Fiske, Charles Albert: 1869 Nov 25; 1870 Feb 28
    Forbes, Edwin: 1867 Nov 20; 1869 Mar 1
    Fraser, "Of Toronto": 1869 Jun 2
    Fraser, James: 1872 Apr 13
    Fraser, John: 1870 Dec 2
    Fredericks, Alfred: 1868 Nov 2; 1873 Dec 9
    Freeborn, Miss: 1875 Feb 2
    Gay, Edward: 1869 Dec 10
    Gifford, [no first name]: 1867 Dec 17; 1869 Jan 20, Mar 11, Nov 22; 1874 Jun 11; 1875 May 22
    Gifford, Robert Swain: 1867 Mar 26, Nov 11; 1868 Mar 23, Dec 1; 1869 Apr 15, Oct 14, Nov 13; 1870 Jan 17, Jan 20, jan 22, Feb 26, Apr 29, May 9, May 28, Jul 8; 1871 Feb 15, Apr 4, May 9, Dec 30; 1872 Feb 27, Dec 10; 1873 Jan 1, Jan 9, Feb 19, Mar 29, May 5, Dec 27; 1874 Jan 17, Jan 30, Mar 2, Mar 5, Mar 23, Apr 30; 1875 Nov 29; 1876 Jan 11, Jan 14, Feb 11, Mar 20, Dec 7, Dec 14, Dec 19; 1877 May 2, May 9, Dec 10, Dec 11; 1878 Jan 25, Feb 15, Feb 23, Mar 9, Mar 11, Mar 20, Apr 18, Mar 10, May 18; 1879 Jan 26, Mar 21, Mar 29; 1880 Feb 25, Mar 26, Apr 14, May 10, May 19, Dec 27, Dec 29, Dec 31
    Gifford, Sanford Robinson: 1867 Feb 19, Mar 6, Dec 4; 1869 Dec 18; 1870 May 28; 1873 Jan 4, Dec 4; 1877 Feb 21; 1878 May 25; 1879 Feb 7, Mar 23, Apr 20, Dec 11; 1880 Apr 8
    Gilbert, Miss: 1873 Jan 25, Dec 18; 1874 Apr 16, Jun 24, Dec 22; 1875 Jan 22, Feb 25, Mar 1; 1876 Jan 24, Apr 4, Apr 12, Apr 13, Apr 17, Nov 13; 1877 Mar 1
    Gilbert, G. A.: 1874 Jan 30
    Greatorex, Eliza Pratt: 1872 Oct 30; 1873 mar 15, Apr 8; 1874 Apr 13, Jun 12, Jun 24
    Greatorex, Kathleen Honora: 1866 Mar 3; 1873 Mar 6, Mar 28; 1874 Jun 8, Jun 10, Jun 12, Jun 13
    Greene, Edward D. E.: 1871 Dec 18; 1872 Jan 27, May 9, May 25, Jul 14; 1873 Mar 8, Nov 17; 1874 Feb 9, Feb 23, Mar 3
    Grey, Henry Peters (?): 1871 Nov 23
    Griswold, Casimir Clayton: 1867 Feb 19; 1870 Jun 7
    Guy, Seymour Joseph: 1868 Jan 31; 1869 Apr 8; 1872 Jan 27
    Hall, George Henry: 1871 Oct 28, Nov 2; 1873 Nov 8; 1875 Apr 9; 1877 Jan 7
    Hart, James M.: 1865 Mar 19, May 10, Jun 20; 1866 Jun 13; 1867 Jan 4, Feb 21, Apr 23, Aug 31, Oct 24, Nov 21; 1868 Jan 2, Apr 16, Jun 23, Nov 7; 1869 Aug 14, Aug 15, Sep 24, Oct 14, Oct 26; 1870 Mar 28, Sep 4, Oct 20, Dec 13; 1871 Feb 23, Jun 26, Oct 3, Nov 9; 1872 Feb 24, Nov 12, Dec 19; 1873 Aug 2, Nov 17; 1874 Mar 7, Nov 19; 1875 Apr 5, May 16, Oct 27; 1876 May 17, Dec 16; 1878 Jun 1